<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erwin&#43;TATP</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erwin&#43;TATP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Geology, Parenthood and Santa Claus</title>
      <link>/post/geology-parenthood-santa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geology-parenthood-santa/</guid>
      <description>After hours of exhausting bike, I finally arrived it the Hong Kong UNISCO Global Geopark at eastern tip of Sai Kung. While I was hiking up and down along the MacLehose Trail, I began to notice something unusual about the park — its lack of local tales. From my own experience, most natural attractions have these kind of stories: this boulder looks like a frog, which according to a local century-old legend was made to be there due to some witchcraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acetone is good</title>
      <link>/post/acetone-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/acetone-is-good/</guid>
      <description>Of the bucket loads of solvents I&amp;rsquo;ve used during my education in chemistry and my current project of device fabrication, acetone is one that fascinates me all the time. I would put it in the second place of &amp;lsquo;My favorite solvent&amp;rsquo; tier list, second only to Dihydrogen Monoxide (a.k.a. the water we drink) and one place higher than aqua regia (that has such a badass name).
The amazing properties of acetone Almost every adult knows that water cannot mix with oil, either from school education, home cooking, or cleaning that greasy patch on the cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/notes/vzkwb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 20:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/vzkwb/</guid>
      <description>Micropub update test. This text should be replaced if the test succeeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/notes/bc0aq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 20:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/bc0aq/</guid>
      <description>This post will be deleted when the test succeeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandate of heaven in modern days</title>
      <link>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</guid>
      <description>Days ago I came upon a meme on YouTube, showing an unfortunate man struck by lightning thrice: Though amusing in a dark way, many comments believed the video it based on was fake because &amp;ldquo;the ground lit up before the bolt appeared&amp;rdquo; and some other reasons. However, I recognized the Chinese watermarks in the frames, and decided to search for the original video - Chinese-speaking media cannot miss this rare</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog and me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I have many useless interests, the biggest of which is procrasitnate.
So I&amp;rsquo;ll just list some brief snippets that I might expand later.
About the ID TATP is short for triacetone triperoxide, a highly explosive organic compound. It was once a somewhat obscure name till recent years, when the terrorists found out they can produce tons of these with Walmart stuff. Like sugar, the molecule only consists of carbon, oxygen and hydrogen, which means it can bypass outdated security scanners and cause tragedies in public transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I start this blog</title>
      <link>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>It all started with OriginLab. Or rather, the hatred towards it.
As a chemistry graduate student with limited programming experience, I had to plot and summarize huge amount of data coming from various scanners - IR, UV-Vis, Current-Voltage, NMR, you name it. And, as a chemistry graduate student trained in China, I picked up pirated versions of OriginLab as my primary tool.
Because &amp;ldquo;everyone else had been using it&amp;rdquo;, they said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>