<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erwin&#43;TATP</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Erwin&#43;TATP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 12:33:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/notes/8nlea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 12:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/8nlea/</guid>
      <description>Test of querying the endpoint for the source content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/notes/yla9n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 12:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/yla9n/</guid>
      <description>This post will be deleted when the test succeeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandate of heaven in modern days</title>
      <link>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</guid>
      <description>Days ago I came upon a meme on YouTube, showing an unfortunate man struck by lightning thrice: Though amusing in a dark way, many comments believed the video it based on was fake because &amp;ldquo;the ground lit up before the bolt appeared&amp;rdquo; and some other reasons. However, I recognized the Chinese watermarks in the frames, and decided to search for the original video - Chinese-speaking media cannot miss this rare</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog and me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I have many useless interests, the biggest of which is procrasitnate.
So I&amp;rsquo;ll just list some brief snippets that I might expand later.
About the ID TATP is short for triacetone triperoxide, a highly explosive organic compound. It was once a somewhat obscure name till recent years, when the terrorists found out they can produce tons of these with Walmart stuff. Like sugar, the molecule only consists of carbon, oxygen and hydrogen, which means it can bypass outdated security scanners and cause tragedies in public transport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I start this blog</title>
      <link>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>It all started with OriginLab. Or rather, the hatred towards it.
As a chemistry graduate student with limited programming experience, I had to plot and summarize huge amount of data coming from various scanners - IR, UV-Vis, Current-Voltage, NMR, you name it. And, as a chemistry graduate student trained in China, I picked up pirated versions of OriginLab as my primary tool.
Because &amp;ldquo;everyone else had been using it&amp;rdquo;, they said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>