<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Erwin&#43;TATP</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Erwin&#43;TATP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acetone is good</title>
      <link>/post/acetone-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/acetone-is-good/</guid>
      <description>Of the bucket loads of solvents I&amp;rsquo;ve used during my education in chemistry and my current project of device fabrication, acetone is one that fascinates me all the time. I would put it in the second place of &amp;lsquo;My favorite solvent&amp;rsquo; tier list, second only to Dihydrogen Monoxide (a.k.a. the water we drink) and one place higher than aqua regia (that has such a badass name).
The amazing properties of acetone Almost every adult knows that water cannot mix with oil, either from school education, home cooking, or cleaning that greasy patch on the cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandate of heaven in modern days</title>
      <link>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mandate-of-heaven-in-modern-days/</guid>
      <description>Days ago I came upon a meme on YouTube, showing an unfortunate man struck by lightning thrice: Though amusing in a dark way, many comments believed the video it based on was fake because &amp;ldquo;the ground lit up before the bolt appeared&amp;rdquo; and some other reasons. However, I recognized the Chinese watermarks in the frames, and decided to search for the original video - Chinese-speaking media cannot miss this rare</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I start this blog</title>
      <link>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-did-i-start-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>It all started with OriginLab. Or rather, the hatred towards it.
As a chemistry graduate student with limited programming experience, I had to plot and summarize huge amount of data coming from various scanners - IR, UV-Vis, Current-Voltage, NMR, you name it. And, as a chemistry graduate student trained in China, I picked up pirated versions of OriginLab as my primary tool.
Because &amp;ldquo;everyone else had been using it&amp;rdquo;, they said.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>